(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-07T03:04:55.318801",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
withØ
作詞・作曲・編曲：K's
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: K's
君の心の中全部見せてよ
Show me everything inside your heart.
何が好きで何が嫌いで僕をどのくらいかな
What you like, what you hate, and how much you like me...
今日はどんな服着てどこで何をしてるの？
What are you wearing today? Where are you and what are you doing?
全部全部隠さないでいいよ 僕に教えて
You don't have to hide anything at all, tell me everything.
平気なフリもしない
I won't even pretend to be okay,
偏見ばっかくだらない
prejudices are just so stupid.
期待しないなんて嘘ばかり
Saying "I don't expect anything" is nothing but lies.
顔色伺い互いに気にして
Reading each other's expressions, worrying about one another...
一人で踊ればいい
We might as well just dance alone.
戻れない
I can't go back...
ずっと欲しかった言葉も
Even the words I've wanted for so long,
シフのままじゃ出てこないなら
if they won't come out of my casual self...
三つ数えて
I'll count to three,
世界が止まれば
and wish the world would stop,
いいのに
how nice that would be.
もう戻れない
I can't go back anymore.
触れて溶け合うくらいの距離感で
At a distance close enough to touch and melt together,
僕のことだけ見ててよ
keep your eyes only on me.
後付けでいいよ
You can make up excuses later,
消えないくらいに ほらね今 ぎゅっとして
just hold me tight enough so it won't fade away.
曖昧だっていいよなんて 僕はわかるから
Saying "it's okay to be ambiguous"... I can see through it.
気づかないふりしてあげるって だからね今
I'll pretend not to notice, so right now...
好きって言ってよ
tell me you love me.
Tell me you love me.
好きって言ってよ
永遠なんてありゃしない
There's no such thing as eternity.
健全なんて嘘ばかり
Being wholesome is nothing but a lie.
期待したいなんてエゴばかり
Wanting to have expectations is pure selfishness.
顔色伺いもギリギリ
Reading your face has reached its limit.
一人で泣けばいい
I should just cry alone,
でも一人は笑えない
but I can't laugh by myself.
ずっと欲しかった言葉も
Even the words I've wanted for so long,
オモテのままじゃ出てこないなら
if they won't come out from the surface...
三つ数えて
I'll count to three,
世界が変われば
and wish the world would change,
いいのに
how nice that would be.
もう戻れない
I can't go back anymore.
ガラガラと音を立てて崩れる
Rattling and crumbling down,
景色の中 落ちてく 見つけ出してよ
falling through the scenery, please find me.
離れないくらいに ほらね今 ぎゅっとして
Hold me tight enough so we won't drift apart.
何回だっていいよなんて 僕はわかるから
Saying "any number of times is fine"... I can see through it.
いつか最後にキスしてくれるって だからねまた
You said you'd kiss me at the end, so once again...
好きって言って
tell me you love me.
夜が明けるまで 話を聞いて
Listen to me until the dawn breaks,
終わらない夢みたいに 輝いて見えた
it shone brightly like an endless dream.
どうか今だけは冷めないで
Please don't let it wake up, at least for now.
冗談じゃないよ
I'm not joking around.
君のいない明日なんて全部いらない
I don't need a tomorrow without you at all.
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
触れて溶け合うくらいの距離感で
At a distance close enough to touch and melt together,
僕のことだけ見ててよ
keep your eyes only on me.
後付けでいいよ
You can make up excuses later,
消えないくらいに ほらね今 ぎゅっとして
just hold me tight enough so it won't fade away.
何回だっていいよなんて 僕はわかるから
Saying "any number of times is fine"... I can see through it.
気づかないふりしてあげるって だからね今
I'll pretend not to notice, so right now...
好きって言ってよ
tell me you love me.
Tell me you love me.
ないない
Nothing, nothing...
はい はい 影ばかり
Yes, yes, only shadows.
ないない
Nothing, nothing...
応 応 遠回り
Yeah, yeah, a detour.
相対 自分 不在
Relativity, my absence,
どこにもいない
I am nowhere to be found.
ないないじゃない
It's not like I don't exist.
曖昧 迷い 愛
Vague, lost love,
色のない藍
colorless indigo.
期待 痛い 以外
Expectation, pain, except for...
人ごとみたい
...it feels like someone else's business.
おかげさま どちらさま
Thank goodness, who are you?
応え様々
Answers vary.
何者でもないまま
Without becoming anyone,
何にもできないまま
unable to do anything,
生きるのは無駄ですが
living is useless, but...
悪いことですか
...is it a bad thing?
ここにいないいないいないのは
The one who isn't, isn't, isn't here...
自分 自分
...is me, myself.
誰も見ない見ない見ないまま
While no one is looking, looking, looking,
吐き捨ててサヨウナラ
spit it out and say goodbye.
嬉しくない 哀しくもない
I'm not happy, nor am I sad.
透明な気分
A transparent feeling.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
My lacking self has no face to show.
ない
Nothing.
笑えないじゃない
I can't even laugh.
灰じゃない 藍合 閉じた眼
Not ash, meeting indigo, closed eyes.
買い被り 期待だけ嫌い
Overestimated, I only hate expectations.
嫌々投げられた賽
The dice thrown reluctantly,
手前は知る由もない
I have no way of knowing.
そこに居たい居たい居たいのも
The one who wants to be, be, be there...
自分 自分
...is me, myself.
味わい 苦い 苦い...
Tasting bitter, bitter...
ない 今更
Not here, at this late hour,
吐き捨てて さようなら
throw it away and say goodbye.
変えられない
I can't change it,
行く先もない
I have nowhere to go,
迷い子を築く
building up a lost child.
間違えてない まだ解らない
I'm not mistaken, I still don't understand,
ない
it's not there.
どうだっていいじゃない
Who cares anyway?
And one more stress, I don't need stress,
up, pa-pa-pa-pa
Trust more, love, stress, and up, what's right,
影も形も いっそなくして しまえばいい
I might as well lose both my shadow and form completely.
また一つ 一つから 始めればいい
I can just start over again, piece by piece.
ここに居ない 居ない 居ないのは 自分 自分
The one who is not here, not here, not here is me, me.
誰も見ない 見ない 見ない今も 吐き捨てて さようなら
Even now, when no one is watching, watching, watching, I throw it away and say goodbye.
嬉しいくらい 哀しくもない
It's so much that it's almost joyful, yet I'm not even sad.
とうに手遅れな傷
A wound that is already far too late to heal.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
My inadequate self has no right to face anyone.
ない ない ないままで ここに居たい 居たい
While remaining lacking, I want to stay, stay right here.
笑いたいじゃない
Don't you want to laugh?
はーい！というわけで、聴いてくれてありがとう！
All right! And with that, thank you so much for listening!
改めて、ハロー！ホロライブ所属0期生、
Once again, hello! From Hololive's Gen 0,
バーチャル高性能ロボットのロボ子だよー！
I'm your virtual high-performance robot, Roboco!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you all so much for coming to my birthday live today!
「高性能？」のハテナみたいなコメント拾わないからね！
I won't be picking up comments questioning my "high-performance"!
だって僕、今日9歳！主役！
Because today, I am 9 years old! I'm the star!
あ、やべ、もう誕生日の答え、質問しようと思ったのに、言っちゃった。
Ah, oops! I was going to ask a quiz question about it, but I already said the answer!
はい！そう、ロボ子なんと、今年で9歳になりました！9歳！
Yes! That's right, Roboco has actually turned 9 years old this year! 9 years old!
ヤバくない？来年もう二桁になる。
Isn't that crazy? Next year, I'll already be in the double digits.
ヤバい、ヤバすぎる！
That's insane, too insane!
ワクワクしてきた！最後の1桁、楽しんでいきたいと思います！
I'm so excited! I want to fully enjoy my last single-digit year!
はい！というわけで、本日のハッシュタグを紹介します！
All right! And with that, let me introduce today's hashtag!
どじょん！本日のハッシュタグは、あ、こっちだった。
Ta-da! Today's hashtag is—ah, it was this way.
えー、ロボ子爆誕2025ですね、皆さん見えましたか？
It's #RobocoBakutan2025! Can everyone see it?
きっと高性能な君たちだったら、
Being the high-performance viewers you are,
もう「ロボ子爆誕2025」をつけて呟いていることでしょう！
I'm sure you're already tweeting with "#RobocoBakutan2025"!
はい！たくさん僕の可愛いスクショと共に、ポストしてくださいね！
Yes! Please post lots of tweets along with cute screenshots of me!
こうして人は循環していくんですよ、ポスト！
That's how people keep the cycle going... with posts!
はい、というわけで、まずは今日はね、僕のオリジナル曲「With Love」から始まって「ないない」を歌ったんですけど
All right! To kick things off today, I started with my original song 'With Love' and then sang 'Nai Nai'...
どうでしたか？
How did you like it?
With LoveのMVと同じね、ウルフカットじゃなくて、
Just like the MV for 'With Love', instead of the wolf cut,
通常の強そうなロングのやつで巻き巻きで行ったんですけれども、え、どうだった？
I went with my usual strong-looking long hair, all curled up! How was it?
良かった？
Was it good?
なんかもう、久々だよね。この、このナイティドレスとかも。
It's really been a while, hasn't it? Since I wore this... this nighty dress.
ウルフカットなんて初めてなんじゃない？ショートカット。
Actually, was that the first time showing the wolf cut? A short haircut!
ショート動画でしか撮らないからね。
Since I usually only record short videos with it.
そう、セクシーでしょ？そして、
Yeah, it's sexy, right? And then...
ステージがなんかスッゴイかっこいい！
The stage looks incredibly cool!
え、カッコ良すぎる！
Oh, it's way too cool!
今回はこんな感じなんですね。今日はなんか色々楽しみなことがいっぱいありそうだけど
So this is the vibe for this stage! It feels like there are so many fun things to look forward to today...
えー、一体何で今日このステージなんだろうな？
But I wonder, why did we end up on this particular stage today?
うーん、なんと後でね…
Hmm, well, actually, later on...
ロボサがいるらしいんですけれども
It seems there are some Robos here,
コメントにいないロボサがいるらしくてですね
and apparently, there's a Robos that is not in the chat.
気になった方は探してみてくださいね
If you're curious, please try and look for it!
いるかな？
Is there one?
うーん...
Hmm...
あれ？ロボサいるかなー？
Huh? Are there any Robos?
あれ？いるかなー？
Huh? Are they really there?
きっと目が... あはは、見つけてる人多い！
Surely... haha, a lot of you have already found it!
正解！正解！ここにいます！
Correct! Correct! It's right here!
ここにいます！
It's right here!
特等席！お前はいったい誰なんだー！
The best seat! Who on earth are you?!
ずっと僕のことをリハ中も見守っててくれてます。ロボサ可愛いねー
It's been watching over me since rehearsals. Robos are so cute!
というわけで、今日は誕生日のために
So, for today's birthday celebration,
いっぱい、いっぱい
I have prepared many, many...
みんな、そして僕が楽しめる歌をたくさんね、ご用意いたしましたので
songs that both you all and I can enjoy,
いっぱい練習もしたので、楽しんでいってください！
and since I practiced a lot, please look forward to them!
はい！この後は、そろそろ
Yes! And next up, it's about time...
一人でも歌うと思うんだけど
I think I'll sing a solo song soon, but...
ゲストも呼んでって、歌っちゃおうかなと思います！
I think I'll also invite some guests and sing with them!
えー、最初は誰だろうなー
So, who's going to be the first guest?
最初は誰だろうなー
I wonder who it'll be...
なんかすごいキスいっぱいにしたい気分になってきた
Somehow I feel like giving lots of kisses now.
なんでだろう？
Why is that?
なんでだ？ちゅっちゅっちゅっ
Why? Chu, chu, chu...
ちゅー！ちゅっちゅっちゅっちゅー！
Chu! Chu-chu-chu-chu!
よくぞお越し下さったご主人様
Welcome, my master.
お隣座って　せーの
Sit next to me, on three...
まい　まい　まい　まい
My, my, my, my
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would be pleased by this?
ねぇ教えて
Hey, tell me,
笑顔でアップップ
with a smile... staring contest!
アイスを溶かしてご苦労様
Thanks for melting the ice.
私とあなたで　せーの
You and I, on three...
だっ　だっ　だっ　だっ
Dat, dat, dat, dat
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would be pleased by this?
ねぇ教えて
Hey, tell me,
笑顔でアップップ
with a smile... staring contest!
ひらり　はらり　女の子
Fluttering, falling, a girl,
ふわり　ふわり　言葉の嘘
softly, softly, a lie in her words.
それってつまり　幼な子
In other words, a young child,
笑顔でアップップ
emotional reality, with a smile... staring contest!
人は見かけによらぬもの
Appearances can be deceiving.
嘘を嘘と見抜けばいい
Just see through the lies.
ちと高鳴る袖裾の皮
The leather of my cuffs throbbing a bit.
パワハラ　セクハラ　アンドモア
Power harassment, sexual harassment, and more.
間違ったご指名を頂くのです
You have chosen the wrong person.
私とあなたで　せーの
You and I, on three...
だっ　だっ　だっ　だっ
Dat, dat, dat, dat
これはだてにご苦労様
Thank you for your hard work for no good reason.
遊びましょう
Let's play,
笑顔でアップップ
with a smile... staring contest!
ひらり　はらり　ここはどこ
Fluttering, falling, where is this?
ふわり　ふわり　そこは内緒
Softly, softly, that's a secret.
それってつまり　幼な子
In other words, a young child,
感情的リアル　笑顔でアップップ
emotional reality, with a smile... staring contest!
お平らにおやすみ
Sleep peacefully,
秘密の種
secret seed.
終わることのない　この世界
Never-ending is this world.
悲しい子供は
Sad children,
寂しい子供は
lonely children,
眠らせて
let them sleep...
おままごと遊びましょう
Let's play house,
笑顔でアップップ
with a smile... staring contest!
ひらり　はらり　女の子
Fluttering, falling, a girl,
ふわり　ふわり　言葉の嘘
softly, softly, a lie in her words.
それってつまり　幼な子
In other words, a young child,
感情的リアル　笑顔でアップップ
emotional reality, with a smile... staring contest!
遊びましょう
Let's play,
笑顔でアップップ
with a smile... staring contest!
アップップ
Staring contest!
アレが世界だって
That's what they call the world,
誰の誰の果て
whose, whose end is it?
答えも欲しいのもエゴでこれだけ
Wanting answers is also just ego, only this.
迷い込んだってしょうがないじゃんね
Even if we get lost, there's nothing we can do, right?
あれは夢だったって思う事よりしたって
Saying that was just a dream is better than just thinking about it,
当然手のもんにしたいけど助けて yeah follower
of course I want to make it mine, but help me, yeah follower.
手探りだけ　うたかたに負け
Only groping in the dark, losing to transient bubbles,
make some make some lucky lucky lucky
あり得よう　割り切れたらさ　終わりいいよ
Let it be possible, if we can just accept it, then the end is fine.
巧みのミトカ はあはあ
Our skillful standards, haa haa...
もういやだ
I'm sick of this already.
満ちる新世界か
Is this a fulfilling new world?
あんた以外は
Anyone but you,
あんた以外はいらないないない
Anyone but you, I don't need, need, need.
張らないのバリア
You're not putting up a barrier?
あるはずの何か
That something that's supposed to be there,
あったならばハッピー ジャンピング いぇ
if it's there, then happy jumping, yeah!
あんたのその手と
Your hand and
あたしのこの手を
this hand of mine...
繋いだら無理にでも 離さないわ
Once connected, even by force, I won't let go.
あんたのその目が
If those eyes of yours
あたしのこの身を
grab this body of mine...
掴んだら 最後見せおこう my love
That's the end, let's show you my love.
これで終わりなんて
For it to end like this,
あがらないままだなんて
and for us to stay down...
だって Pump Pump
Because pump pump,
どうにかなっちゃってって願って 願って ね
wishing things would turn out somehow, wishing, wishing, hey...
レスキューしたい？リセッション
Do you want to rescue? Recession.
なーも我慢できん ペンペンペン 痛いって ばいばいベイビー
I can't endure anything anymore, spank, spank, spank! "It hurts," bye-bye baby.
まあ言うて聞いてるけどな ブルベ夏なんで関係ないなー
Well, I'm listening to what you say, but I'm cool summer so it doesn't matter.
誰よりもネコ ペットない？もう結構
More of a cat than anyone. No pet? No thanks.
脚は脚だ 見といてよレイディ
Legs are legs, take a good look, lady!
もう今日で終わらせたいなって
I feel like ending it today,
リスタートできたらって
wishing I could restart...
でももう無理よ もう
But it's impossible now, already...
what’s on your mind?
What's on your mind?
ありおりはべりいまそかり さあ売りよ
To be, to exist... Come on, sell it!
巧みのミトカ はあはあ
Our skillful standards, haa haa...
もういやだ
I'm sick of this already.
満ちる新世界か
Is this a fulfilling new world?
あんた以外は
Anyone but you,
あんた以外はいらないないない
Anyone but you, I don't need, need, need.
張らないのバリア
You're not putting up a barrier?
あるはずの何か
That something that's supposed to be there,
あったならばハッピー ジャンピング いぇ
if it's there, then happy jumping, yeah!
あんたのその手と
Your hand and
あたしのこの手を
this hand of mine...
繋いだら無理にでも 離さないわ
Once connected, even by force, I won't let go.
あんたのその目が
If those eyes of yours
あたしのこの身を
grab this body of mine...
掴んだら 最後見せおこう my love
That's the end, let's show you my love.
なーなーもういいわ
Hey, hey, that's enough.
最後見せおこう my love
Let's show you my love at the end.
半端なら K.O. ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you're half-hearted, it's a K.O. If you want to float around, go ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether you cry or laugh, love me, okay?
ほら せーの 手を響かせろ
Come on, one-two! Make your hands resonate!
なんだかなってつまんないこともあるでしょう
There must be times when things are somewhat boring, right?
ノリノリなんだの？半信半疑だそう
What's with this high tension? Let's be half-in, half-doubt.
夜な夜なトローリーにバットハットだろうが
Late at night, whether it's a trolley or a bad hat,
おこられておちて いぇい
getting scolded and falling down, yay!
そろそろ一回もっとがんばって
It's about time to work harder once more,
お風呂までもっとがんばって
do your best until it's bath time!
繋がろう一人より二人
Let's connect, two are better than one,
増えたら足し 心配ないよ
if we increase, we add up, no need to worry!
オーライのっけてドンマイマイに
Alright, jump on, don't mind it,
なんだいみんなでなんかやっちゃえば？
why don't we all just do something?
案外サクッと行っちゃいそう
Surprisingly, it might go smoothly!
半端なら K.O. ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you're half-hearted, it's a K.O. If you want to float around, go ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether you cry or laugh, love me, okay?
ほら せーの 手を響かせろ
Come on, one-two! Make your hands resonate!
今夜はアセンブリー
Tonight is assembly!
踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独を先に舞い降り
Start dancing, start dancing, flutter down ahead of loneliness.
胃のなかまで押し寄せる心配バイバイレッドゾーン
The worries rushing into my stomach, bye-bye Red Zone!
隣でトントンどうぞ
Come on, tap next to me,
そ今日の化粧バンバン
today's makeup is looking great!
最高に掴んで しまっちゃうでしょう Oh yeah
We'll grab the best and lock it away, oh yeah!
アッパーカットなテンション
An uppercut-like tension,
ねえ 参っちゃってんのさ ほら
hey, we're totally overwhelmed, look!
ドバッと吹き出すのは
What gushes out with a splash
ほら 胸の独り言
is, look, the monologue of my heart!
別に関心ない
I don't really care,
そこに限界ない
there are no limits there.
注ぎ込んでデポデポ上
Pouring it in, deposit, deposit, going up!
合図を奏でて プラプラプラプラ yeah
Play the signal, pla-pla-pla-pla yeah!
ほら熱くなって 夜をGOだ
Look, get hot, and go into the night!
抱いていこう
Let's embrace it!
pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa pa
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
半端なら K.O.
If it's half-hearted, it's a K.O.
イェイ、イェイ、イェイ、イェイ、イェイ！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
踊りゃんせ 踊りゃんせ 孤独な心臓 舞い降りて
Dance, dance, descending upon a lonely heart.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
怒りまで 押し寄せて 宵も合点さ バリラ
Even anger rushes in, tonight is fully understood, bari la.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
ただ起こせよ 一途
Just stir it up, with all your heart.
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh
世界まで お元気で ここらでバイバイライダ
Be well, world, let's say goodbye here, rider.
よぉ、うなだれてるその兄ちゃん
Hey, you, hanging your head, brother.
なんか辛いことあったんか？
Did something painful happen?
俺で良ければ話してくんない
If you don't mind, why not talk to me?
力になるぜ
I'll help you out.
一体どんなことがあった？
What on earth happened?
それ聞いて話して兄弟
Tell me about it, brother.
これをやるから元気出しな
Have this, and cheer up.
金ならまた今度でいいさ
As for the money, next time is fine.
シャンティ シャンティ シャンティ...
Shanti Shanti Shanti...
ハッピー ハッピー ハッピー キャンディ メニー メニー マニー
Happy happy happy candy, many many money.
眠らない夜の街のダンスのすべてがナワバリ
All of the dance in the city that never sleeps is our territory.
老若男女お引き合わせ ヤツが来たらそっと出会い
Men and women, young and old, introduced to each other. When he comes, we quietly meet.
今夜も来たのかい
Have you come again tonight?
こっちについてきな
Follow me this way.
お気に召したかい
Did you like it?
代金はこれくらい
The price is about this much.
え、え、え、え
Eh, eh, eh, eh.
こっちについてきな
Follow me this way.
払えないのかい
Can't you pay?
ならばしょうがない
Well, then it can't be helped.
こっちについてきな
Follow me this way.
歪に割れたソヴカ 剥がれたおんな
A warp-cracked sovka, peeled-off kindness.
嗄れた看板 掲げたおんな
A hoarse signboard, a hoisted shop name.
たかがマイクで騒がれた夜じゃ
On a night when people got loud over just a mic,
ハナから奴の思惑通りだ
it was within his expectations from the start.
イカれてる目算、途中
A crazy estimation, halfway through,
血塗れても胃納得？
are you satisfied even if bloodied?
提灯、燈籠、咲かせた果て 猛進の芯、汚されたまえ
Paper lanterns, decorative lanterns, blooming to the end. The core of blind rush, let it be defiled.
黙れ、座れ、黙れ、座れよ
Shut up, sit down, shut up, sit down!
殴れ、殴れ、殴れ、殴れよ
Strike, strike, strike, strike!
縛れ、縛れ、縛れ、縛れよ
Bind, bind, bind, bind!
バラせ、バラせ、バラせよ
Dismantle, dismantle, dismantle!
今夜のあの子は
How was that girl tonight?
お気に召したかい
Did you like her?
代金はこれくらい
The price is about this much.
生きていれば合格
If you're alive, you pass,
死んでいれば上等
if you're dead, all the better.
すべてが望むがままに転がり 手にした幸せはどうだい？
If everything rolls as you wish, how is the happiness you obtained?
どっちを向いてんだ
Which way are you looking?
よぉ、うなだれてるそのお嬢ちゃん
Hey, you, hanging your head, young lady,
俺で良ければ話してくんない
if you don't mind, why not talk to me?
はーい！というわけで
Yes! And with that...
かっこいいでしょ？
Isn't it cool?
はい！こちらがロボ子の新衣装となります！
Yes! This is RoboCo's new outfit!
見て、下から！超かっこいいの！
Look, from below! It's super cool!
どうよ？え、サングラス似合いすぎだわ
How is it? Eh, the sunglasses suit me way too well!
やばい、みんなが恋しちゃう
Oh no, everyone's going to fall in love with me.
俺に惚れると火傷するぜ
If you fall for me, you'll get burned.
やべ、草すぎる。笑わないで、笑うのやめてね
Oh no, that's way too hilarious. Don't laugh, stop laughing!
はい！というわけで
Yes! And with that...
見て、これ！かっこいいでしょ！
Look at this! Isn't it cool?
なんかさ、指ついてんだけど、まだよく見えないね
There's something on my fingers, but you can't see it clearly yet.
まだ、まだよく見えないね！
Not yet, you still can't see it clearly!
まだ！まだよく見えないね！
Not yet! You still can't see it clearly!
え、おどの時にカラーライズ衣装からチェンジしたんだけど
Well, I changed from my colorized outfit during "Odo"...
チェンジした瞬間、ちゃんとみんな分かった？
...but did everyone notice the exact moment I changed?
沸いてくれました？
Did you get hyped?
一瞬だったでしょ？
It was just a moment, right?
うれしい！
I'm so happy!
可愛い？かっこいい？ねえ。
Is it cute? Is it cool? Right?
これ、なんか両方あるよね。かっこいいし可愛いよね。
It has both, right? It's cool and cute.
プリティでクールなの、これ。
It's pretty and cool.
いっぱい見て、いっぱい見て。足からちょっと見てく？
Look at it lots, look at it lots. Shall we look starting from the feet?
おお、見っ、え？やばい。かっこよすぎるんだが。
Oh, look, eh? Crazy. It's just too cool.
見て、これ。ロボット特有のさ、
Look at this. This is unique to robots,
この、これ人間だったら多分めっちゃ歩きづらいんじゃん？
this... if it were a human, it'd probably be super hard to walk in, right?
みんな多分歩けないよね、この靴。僕歩けるんだけどさ。
Everyone probably couldn't walk in these shoes. I can walk in them, though.
うお、この靴で、多分僕走ったら多分めっちゃ倍コケると思うから、歩きます。
Whoa, if I run in these shoes, I'll probably fall twice as much, so I'll walk.
どう？どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
はい、そして上からね。かっこよく決まって、ベルト、
Yes, and from the top. Posing coolly, belts...
あればあるだけいいですから！いっぱい着けてもらいました。
The more belts, the better! I had them put on a lot.
今回マジで装飾品もね、かっこいい、キラキラ。
This time, the accessories are seriously cool and sparkly too.
金色のネックレス。これ、龍とか雷が付いてるのかな？
The gold necklace. Does it have a dragon or lightning on it?
うん。
Yeah.
あとなんか、姿がちょっとおかしくなってるけど。僕の新衣装に合わせたロボサーがイヤリングになり、
Also, my appearance is a bit weird, but... Robosa, customized for my new outfit, became an earring,
新しい丸眼鏡は、ちょっとクールで装飾品もいっぱい付いてるし、
and the new round glasses are a bit cool and have lots of accessories on them too,
何よりこの、でっかいお団子可愛いでしょ？もふもふもふもふ。
above all, these huge hair buns are cute, right? Fluffy, fluffy, fluffy.
僕、毛量多いの大好き！
I love having lots of hair!
ね。このもふもふ可愛いよね。
Right? This fluffiness is cute, isn't it?
これ脱げるのかって？ええ？
Can I take this off? Eh?
だって指だってまだちゃんと見れてないもんね。
Because we haven't even properly seen my fingers yet.
脱げちゃうのかな？後で。
Maybe I'll take it off? Later.
後でお楽しみにしててください。
Please look forward to it.
はい、というわけで、え、でも、
Yes, and so, eh, but...
ライブ以来だよ、カラーライズ衣装を着たの。
It's been since the live concert that I wore my Colorize outfit.
かっこよかったでしょ？ギャル。
Wasn't it cool? Gyaru.
ね。めちゃめちゃ映えてたよね。
Right? It really stood out.
燃えよチャイナもね。
And Moeyo China too.
もう早くね、エリザベスが、3Dモデル出ることを僕待ってるから！プレズ！
I'm waiting so impatiently for Elizabeth's 3D model to come out! Please!
でも一緒に歌えてすごい楽しかった。ありがとうね、みんな。
But it was so much fun singing together. Thank you, everyone.
はい。そしてオドトちゃんとソロも歌いましたけれども、
Yes. And I sang solo and with Odoto-chan too,
爆上げかっこよすぎロボ子さ。
but Roboco is way too cool, hyping it up.
一定数いますからね、ロボ子の低音が大好きすぎる民たち。
There's a certain number of people who absolutely love Roboco's low register.
うん、いつもありがとう。すごい嬉しい。僕も気持ちよく歌えました。
Yeah, thanks as always. I'm so happy. I felt great singing it.
あ、ところで、ステージがなんか進化してドラゴン君が生まれてたの気づきました？
Oh, by the way, did you notice the stage evolved and a dragon was born?
こいつ。どっから来たんやね、お前。
This guy. Where did you come from?
ロボさ、食われちゃいそうだよね。
Looks like I'm about to get eaten.
一回ロボサーをドラゴンの口の中に入れてやろうかね、ちょっと悩んだ。
I actually hesitated for a second whether to put Robosa in the dragon's mouth.
でも入れなかった。僕偉い。
But I didn't. I'm so good.
あいつの上に乗らせすぎだろ。うん。
Riding on top of that guy too much, right? Yeah.
というわけでですね、
So, actually,
もう次の歌も歌いたいんですけれども、
I want to sing the next song soon,
せっかくね、この衣装なので、
but since I'm in this outfit,
なんかゲストの中にめっちゃシナジーある奴がいるらしいんですよ。
apparently there's someone among the guests who has amazing synergy.
歌っちゃおうかな。
Maybe we should sing together.
ね、ドラゴン君。歌いたいよね。
Right, Dragon-kun? You want to sing, don't you?
ね。
Right?
歌いたい。
"I want to sing."
って言ってる気がするんで。
I feel like that's what he's saying.
じゃあ早速呼んでいきましょう！
So let's call them over right away!
みーみーみなせー！
Mi- Mi- Minase!
ロボ子久しぶり。お誕生日おめでとう。
Long time no see, Roboco. Happy birthday.
みなちゃん、ありがとう！ねえ見て見て、新衣装。
Mina-chan, thank you! Hey, look, look at my new outfit!
めっちゃ可愛い。めっちゃ可愛い。
It's super cute. It's super cute.
一緒に「いーあるふぁんくらぶ」歌おう！
Let's sing "Yi Er Fanclub" together!
いいよ。
Sure.
うっ、はっ、うっ、はっ
Uh! Ha! Uh! Ha!
神戸 中央区 元町
In Motomachi, Chuo Ward, Kobe,
駅前
in front of the station,
今日から ドキドキ ニーハオ講座
starting today, a heart-pounding Ni-Hao class.
大人 中高生 おばちゃんに
For adults, high schoolers, and grandmas,
こんにちは
"Hello."
「ダメダメ ここでは あなたも ニーハオ！」
"No, no, here, you say 'Ni-Hao' too!"
マジで テキスト 三ページ
Seriously, on page three of the textbook,
早くも
already...
も
...too.
ここはとにかく羞恥心に勝つぞ
Anyway, I'll conquer my shyness here!
一万三千の月謝は安くない
A monthly fee of thirteen thousand isn't cheap!
ハオハオ大家ご機嫌いかが
Hao-hao landlord, how are you doing?
お母さん
"Mother"
お馬さん
"Horse"
マーマー
Mama
ここはどこ
"Where is this?"
君は誰
"Who are you?"
シェイ
Who?
大好きなワン・リーホンに
To my favorite Wang Leehom...
大好きだって言うため
so I can tell him "I love you"...
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
Hi-Hi China, a slightly dreamy feeling,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Yi-Ar Fanclub!
だんだん君と同じ言葉が
Gradually, the same words as yours...
使えるね
I can use them!
『ウォーアイニー』言えるかな
I wonder if I can say "I love you".
ねえ見て りゅーちゃん
Hey, look, Ryu-chan!
龍
A dragon!
龍、くっ...
Dragon, grr...
りゅーちゃん、龍、くっ...
Ryu-chan, dragon, grr...
ふっ
Hmph.
そこで知り合った女子高生
The high school girl I met there...
ミカちゃん
Mika-chan!
曰く 台湾でジェイ・チョウのコンサート
She says Jay Chou has a concert in Taiwan...
それは行かなきゃだめだ
I absolutely have to go!
ところで
By the way...
ミカちゃんしれっと言ってるけど
Mika-chan says it so casually, but
海外だよ
it's abroad!
マジでエンジンかかってんな
She's really revved up!
ミカちゃん
Mika-chan!
ここはとにかく便乗して頑張るか
For now, I guess I'll tag along and do my best!
六万数千の旅費も安くない
The travel expense of sixty-odd thousand isn't cheap either.
それではバイト探さなきゃ
Well then, I have to find a part-time job!
すみません お嬢さん
Excuse me, miss!
小籠包
Xiao Long Bao!
これ一つ いくらでしょう
How much is one of these?
シェイシェイ
Xie xie!
天国のレスリー・チャンに
To Leslie Cheung in heaven...
おやすみなさいって言うため
so I can say "Good night"...
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
Hi-Hi China, a slightly dreamy feeling,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Yi-Ar Fanclub!
だんだん君の伝えたい気持ちが
Gradually, the feelings you want to convey...
わかってく
I can understand them!
ウォーアイニー
Wo ai ni...
憧れて 夢中になって
Admiring you, getting obsessed...
一ヶ月 二ヶ月
One month, two months...
一ヶ月
One month,
二ヶ月
two months,
半年過ぎた
half a year has passed!
リア友は少し減ったけど
My real-life friends decreased a bit, but...
それもしかたないや保存
that can't be helped anyway!
いやあーーー
Yeahhh!
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
Hi-Hi China, a slightly dreamy feeling,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Yi-Ar Fanclub!
だんだん君と同じ言葉が
Gradually, the same words as yours...
使えるね
I can use them!
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
Hi-Hi China, a slightly dreamy feeling,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ保存
Yi-Ar Fanclub!
だんだん君の伝えたい気持ちが
Gradually, the feelings you want to convey...
わかってく
I can understand them!
『ウォーアイニー』言わせてよ
Let me say "I love you"!
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
Yi-Ar Fanclub!
『ウォーアイニー』言えるかな
I wonder if I can say "I love you".
ウォーアイニー
I love you.
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
わあ、びっくりした！ありがとう！
Whoa, you startled me! Thank you!
不意打ちはやめてね
Don't surprise me like that!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
あはは、ありがとう！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Ahaha, thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
素敵
Lovely.
素敵じゃない？あなた
Don't you look lovely?
どこが素敵？
What's lovely about it?
もちろん
Of course...
太もも
the thighs.
ねえー！
Hey!
全部そこじゃないの！
It's not all about that!
もちろん保存
Of course...
太もも
the thighs.
太ももフェチなのかな？保存
Are you a thigh fetishist?
太もも好き
I like thighs.
どこら辺？太もも
Which part of the thighs?
エッチだから
Because they're sexy.
ねぇー！
Hey!
僕大好きそういうの。ちょっと露出してるの。ちょっとだけ。
I really love that kind of stuff. Showing a little skin. Just a little bit.
あは、そっか
Ah, I see.
で、素敵じゃないですか？
And don't you look lovely?
いいよね！でもあなたもね！
It's great! But so do you!
あ、そう？保存
Oh, really?
ここ、ここ好き、この、ここ！
Here, I like here! This, right here!
お揃いです
They're matching.
ここフェチ、フェチズム、たまんね！
I have a fetish for this... fetishism, it's irresistible!
たまんね？
Irresistible?
最高だ！
It's the best!
人のこと言えないな
You're one to talk.
お互いそういう絡みしかできない
We can only interact like this with each other.
やばい、長年の適当な絡みになっちまってよ
Oh no, our interactions have gotten so casual over the years.
適当な緑仙です
I am the casual Ryusen.
あ、緑仙が来てくれました！
Ah, Ryusen has come!
どうも
Hello.
ピッタリでしょ、今回！保存
It's a perfect match this time, right?
ね！保存
Right!
もう呼びたくて呼びたくて仕方なかった
I wanted to invite you so, so badly.
嬉しい。何？このかっこいいポーズ？
I'm glad. What is this cool pose?
歌えたのがね、まず嬉しいよ
First of all, I'm glad we could sing together.
え、そうだよね！確かに！保存
Ah, that's true! Absolutely!
歌ったことないんだよね？
We've never sung together, right?
そうなんですよ。歌ったことなかったから。
That's right. We've never sung together before.
何これ？
What is this?
分からない、なんか喋りながらポーズしておこうと思って。
I don't know, I just thought we should strike a pose while talking.
待て
Wait.
待て、待て、みんな落ち着け！
Wait, wait, everyone calm down!
落ち着いて
Calm down.
写真は撮っていい？勝手に
Can you take photos? Feel free to.
いい感じで撮っていいよ
You can take them looking good.
うん、勝手に！
Yeah, feel free!
スクショを撮って、タグをつけて！
Take screenshots, tag them,
投稿してほしい！
and post them!
ハッシュタグは何ですか？
What is the hashtag?
ハッシュタグは...
The hashtag is...
そんなことは、ここを見れば分かるだろう！
You'll know if you just look here!
端折らないでよ。えー、長年だと手抜くんですか？
Don't skip it. Eh, do you get lazy after all these years?
あはは！そんなことないです！
Ahaha! That's not true!
何ですか？途中の、
What was that in the middle?
ん？途中の...
Hm? In the middle of...
あ、上、上を指して、あなた
Ah, you pointed up, up.
だってあなたの名前って、緑仙じゃないですか？
Because your name is Ryusen, isn't it?
緑仙ですよ。
It is Ryusen.
龍、あ、龍。
Dragon, ah, dragon.
あ、龍。
Ah, a dragon.
あ、龍、あ、龍、あ、龍、ほらほら龍。
Ah, dragon, ah, dragon, ah, dragon, look, a dragon.
「浮いてる」ってなっちゃう。
They're going to say, "It's floating."
だってあそこ僕に任されたんだもん。
But I was entrusted with that part!
しかもさ、僕のことさ「龍ちゃん」って呼んでるよね、今日。
And besides, you're calling me "Ryu-chan" today.
龍ちゃん。今日、今日はね。
Ryu-chan. Just for today.
でも普段は「緑」とか言うんですよ。
But normally she calls me "Midori."
今日だけ「龍ちゃん！」とか言って。
Only today, she's like, "Ryu-chan!"
「龍ちゃん！」
"Ryu-chan!"
やばい、なんかお馴染み面で近寄ってきたなと思って、すごいドキドキしてます。
Oh my, when you approached me with that familiar face, my heart was pounding so fast.
本当？可愛くぶっちゃった？
Really? Did I act too cute?
可愛い。このポーズ可愛い、これ。
Cute. This pose is really cute.
え、可愛いでしょ？
Eh, cute, right?
龍ちゃん見てみて！
Ryu-chan, look, look!
えー、可愛い。
Aww, cute.
やっちゃった。
I did it.
ね、みんな僕の分も褒めてあげてください。僕はあまり褒めないんで。
Hey everyone, praise her on my behalf too. I don't praise her much.
え？褒めろよ。
Eh? Praise me!
褒めるよ。
I do praise you.
可愛い、本当に可愛い。
Cute, really cute.
おい、龍ちゃんもあざといポーズしろ。
Hey, Ryu-chan, you do a cute pose too.
え、一緒にしよ。
Eh, let's do it together.
しよ。
Let's do it.
え、可愛い！キュルン。
Oh, so cute! Kyurun.
キュルン。
Kyurun.
キュル？
Kyuru?
カッコいい、可愛い、最高じゃない。
Cool, cute, isn't it the best?
いいじゃないですか。
Isn't it great?
いいじゃ、え、なんかポーズしようよ。
It's good, eh, let's do some pose.
希望あれば。
If you have any requests.
何なりと。
Anything.
パンチ？
A punch?
パンチ？あ、いつもね、クソ雑魚パンチしたもんね。我々。
Punch? Ah, we always do the "super weak punch", don't we?
超強パンチ。
Super strong punch.
超強パンチ？
Super strong punch?
うん、かかってこいよ。
Yeah, bring it on!
かかってこいよ、おお、最高。強そう。
Bring it on, oh, awesome. Looks strong.
強そう。
Looks strong.
本当に強そうになっちゃった。
It really ended up looking strong.
強そう。
Looks strong.
なんか撃退したいリプライとかあったらね、これ使っても。
If there are any replies you want to fight off, you can use this.
ね、使ってください。
Yeah, please use it.
かかってこいかい？
Bring it on, will ya?
倒します。
We'll defeat them.
そう、我々は。
Yes, we...
こい、こい。
Bring it on, bring it on.
クソリプ。
Shit replies.
そう、クソリプ倒します。
Yes, we'll defeat shit replies.
え、見て。龍ちゃん好きそう。
Eh, look. Ryu-chan would like this.
可愛い、マジで可愛い。
Cute, seriously cute.
好きそう。
Looks like you would.
素敵。
Lovely.
いいね、ちょっとポーズはさておき、素敵よ。
Nice, putting the pose aside, it's lovely.
やった。
Yay.
ポーズも褒めて。
Praise the pose too.
この適当なポーズも褒めて。
Praise this random pose too.
めちゃくちゃいい感じでしょ？強そう。おお、おお。
It's a really good vibe, right? Looks strong. Oh, oh.
おおー！
Ohhh!
え、靴可愛い。
Eh, the shoes are cute.
え、止まんないよ、もう、褒めだしたら。
Eh, it won't stop once we start praising.
やばい。
Oh dear.
やばい、やばい、やばい、さわ、嬉しい。
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear, so happy.
嬉しい。
Happy.
今日呼んで良かった。
I'm glad I invited you today.
マジで呼んでくれてありがとう。
Seriously, thank you for inviting me.
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
今日ね、まだ、ふふ。
Today, we still... hehe.
いや、締めるの下手か！と思って。
I was thinking, "Are you bad at wrapping up?!"
頑張ってね。
Good luck!
頑張る、バイバイ。
I will, bye-bye.
バイバイ、お疲れ様。
Bye-bye, thanks for your hard work.
あいつマジで本当に雑なんだよ。
She is seriously so careless/casual.
はい、というわけで、緑でした。龍ちゃんでもなんでも呼んであげてください。
Alright, so that was Midori. Please call me Ryu-chan or whatever you like.
じゃあロボ子、次、頑張りますんで。うー、パンチ！
Well then, Roboco is up next, she'll do her best. Ugh, punch!
I want to tell you, yeah
泡と消えそうなチャアイナ
China, fading away like bubbles
I want to tell you, yeah
泡の弾けるチャイナ
China, popping like bubbles
ロボ子、誕生日おめでとう！
Roboco, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
春茶、バーチャルの世界へようこそ！
Harucha, welcome to the virtual world!
春茶の明日真っ黒になっちゃった。
Harucha's tomorrow has become pitch black.
真っ黒真っ黒。
Pitch black, pitch black.
マイク、マイク。
Microphone, microphone.
いってきます！
Here I go!
ウォーウォー
Woah woah
ウォーアイニー にーにー
Woah ai ni, ni, ni
ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー あなたに
Woah ai ni, woah ai ni, woah ai ni, to you
いたって簡単に落ちる
So very easily falling for you
ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー
Woah ai ni, woah ai ni, woah ai ni
I want to tell you, yeah
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China, fading away like bubbles
I want to tell you, yeah
泡の弾けるチャイナ
China, popping like bubbles
扇状の門に 君に
At the fan-shaped gate, to you
ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ひそかに
Woah ai ni, woah ai ni, woah ai ni, secretly
中東の国に 終わる
Ending in a Middle Eastern country
ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー
Woah ai ni, woah ai ni, woah ai ni
そんな奴やめちゃいな
Dump a guy like that
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China, China advice
もう私のこと虜にして
Already making a captive of me
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China advice
I want to tell you, yeah
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China, fading away like bubbles
I want to tell you, yeah
泡の弾けるチャイナ
China, popping like bubbles
戦場の境界に潜む
Lurking at the borders of the battlefield
ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー そう曖昧に
Woah ai ni, woah ai ni, woah ai ni, so ambiguously
往来の限界に挑む
Challenging the limits of traffic
ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー ウォーアイニー
Woah ai ni, woah ai ni, woah ai ni
ねえそろそろやめちゃいな
Hey, it's about time you dump him
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China, China advice
いい加減に大人にな
It's time to grow up already
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China advice
I want to tell you, yeah
泡と消えそうなチャイナ
China, fading away like bubbles
I want to tell you, yeah
泡の弾けるチャイナ
China, popping like bubbles
そんな奴やめちゃいな
Dump a guy like that
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China, China advice
バイバイする
Say bye-bye...
もう私の虜になりなさい
...and fall for me already.
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China, China Advice.
さあ受けよう
Come on, let's take it.
手玉に取っちゃいな
Wrap him around your finger.
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China, China Advice.
あぁ 私の虜になりなさい
Ah, fall for me already.
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ そう チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, yes, China Advice.
はるちゃん！
Haru-chan!
嬉しい、一緒に歌えて！
I'm so happy we got to sing together!
楽しかった。
That was so much fun.
楽しかった！ありがとう！
It was fun! Thank you!
ありがとう、こちらこそ。
Thank you, likewise.
はるちゃんさ、そこから出れないの？
Haru-chan, can you not come out of there?
そう、そう。ここがうち。
Yeah, yeah. This is my home.
うそー。
No way!
すごいよね、これね。
This is pretty amazing, isn't it?
え、すごいよね。
Yeah, it really is.
というわけで、今日ははるちゃんがゲストにきてくれました！
So today, Haru-chan has joined us as a guest!
こんにちは、はるちゃんです。
Hello, I'm Haru-chan.
はるちゃんです。
I'm Haru-chan.
はるちゃんがさ、すごいさ、みんなも、
People are probably like,
「え、そこ設定あるの？」ってめっちゃ思われると思うよね。
"Wait, there's a setting for that?"
1回だけね、ポストとかでね、した。
We posted about it once.
そう。
Yeah.
お土産ね。
The souvenir.
そう、お土産をね、あげたの。
Right, I gave you a souvenir.
そう、もらった。
Yes, I received it.
そう、で、実ははるちゃんからも、ロボ子はお土産をもらってる。
Right, and I actually got a souvenir from Haru-chan too.
確かにあげたわ。
I certainly did give you one.
そう、でもそれはポストしてない。
Yeah, but I didn't post about that one.
そう、なんだかんだ、結構ね、遊んでたりもしましたからね。
Well, we've actually hung out quite a bit, you see.
今回はお呼びしました。どうでしたか？
So I invited her today. How was it?
どうでしたか？
How was it?
え、私に聞いてる、今？
Wait, are you asking me right now?
え、みんなに聞いてる。
No, I'm asking everyone.
あ、みんなにか。
Ah, everyone.
え、でもどうだった？一緒に歌って。
But really, how was it singing together?
めっちゃ楽しかった。
It was super fun.
え、嬉しい！僕も楽しかった！
I'm so glad! I had fun too!
ね、初めて歌ったよね？
We sang together for the first time, right?
うん、うん、歌ったよね。
Yeah, yeah, we did.
歌ったよね。
We did, indeed.
歌った。
We sang.
こういう場所でね。
In a place like this.
ね、そうだよね。
Yeah, that's right.
だってさ、声質が結構さ、近いからさ、
Since our voice qualities are pretty close,
あ、絶対にこれに似合うやんと思って、
I thought this song would definitely suit us,
今回はチャイナアドバイス、呼びました。
so we did "China Advice" this time.
ロボコが決めたの？
Did you decide on it, Roboco?
うん、そうだよ。
Yeah, I did.
あ、そうなんだ。
Ah, I see.
構成案でしょ？
In the event plan, right?
そう、構成案。さすが。
Yes, in the event plan. As expected.
はるちゃんがさ、珍しいんだよ。僕のこと「ロボコ」って呼ぶの。
Haru-chan is unique because she calls me "Roboco."
え、そうなんだ、珍しいんだね。
Oh, really? Is that rare?
あんまりいないの、マジで！
Seriously, barely anyone does!
さっき聞いてびっくりした。
I was surprised to hear that just now.
そう、もうナチュラルにずっと「ロボコ」なの。
Yeah, you naturally just always call me "Roboco."
そう、ずっとロボコ。
Yes, always Roboco.
逆に何？何が多いの？
What is it usually then? What do people call you?
えー、ロボちゃんとか、ロボ、やっぱ先輩とか。
Like "Robo-chan," "Robo," or "Senpai."
あ、ね、それはちょっとよくわからない。
Oh, yeah, I don't really get that one.
先輩なの、ロボコ。
Roboco is your senior, you know.
そう、先輩なんだよ、一応。
Yes, I am technically your senior.
えー、ねえねえ、なんか...
Hey, hey, look...
これ、本当にやりたかったけど、できないの、忘れてた。
I really wanted to do this but forgot how.
ハート？
A heart?
ハート作ります。
Let's make a heart.
ハート！
Heart!
あ、いけそうじゃね？
Wait, doesn't it look doable?
みんな、みんな写真撮って！
Everyone, take a picture!
みんな写真撮って！
でもいい感じやん。
But it looks really nice.
え、可愛い。
Oh, so cute.
え、どう、これ？新しい衣装なんですけれども。
So, how is it? This is my new outfit.
超可愛いと思います。
I think it's super cute.
え、はるちゃん的にお勧めのポーズとかあったら撮っちゃうんだけど。
If you have any poses to recommend, I'll strike them.
え、ちょっと、あれやって、上目遣い。
Um, do that one, look up at me.
上目遣い？
Looking up?
はるちゃん...
Haru-chan...
はるちゃん、
Haru-chan,
いっぱい遊んで。
play with me a lot.
可愛い！
So cute!
いっぱい遊ぼう。
Let's play a lot.
でも手はごついんだね。
But your hands are pretty tough-looking.
そう、めちゃくちゃかっこいい。見て！
Yeah, they're super cool. Look!
え、でも好きでしょ、こういうの。
But you like this kind of thing, right?
うん、いいな。
Yeah, it's nice.
ごつい。かっこいい。これ、めちゃ高い。
Tough. Cool. These are super expensive.
高いんだ。
They're expensive?
そう、高そう。
Yeah, they look expensive.
めっちゃ高い。多分、パパが作ってくれた。
Super expensive. My papa made them for me, probably.
パパもすごいの？
Your papa is amazing too?
うん、パパもすごいな。
Yeah, my papa is amazing too.
お団子もさ、超可愛くない？
Also, aren't the hair buns super cute?
超可愛い。
Super cute.
お団子可愛いでしょ、見て。
The hair buns are cute, right? Look.
髪量がめちゃめちゃあるんです、ロボコ。
I have tons of hair, you know.
ね。
Yeah.
後ろから見るとすごいでしょ。
It looks amazing from behind, right?
ポポポポポン。
Po-po-po-po-pon.
全部可愛い。
Everything's cute.
え、やった！オールパーフェクトじゃん！
Yay! It's all perfect then!
パーフェクト。
Perfect.
はるちゃん、これ途中でやってたの気づいた？
Haru-chan, did you notice me doing this earlier?
これ、歌中、やってた、気づいた？
Did you notice I was doing this during the song?
なんか、こっち見てやってたよね、しかも。
You were even looking this way while doing it.
そう、気づいてーって、カメラ目線でやってた。
Yeah, like "Notice me!" I was looking at the camera.
そうだ、そうだ。
That's right, that's right.
というわけで、ロボ...
So anyway, Robo...
おめでとう、本当に。
Congratulations, seriously.
え、なんか、何何、何、何？
Wait, what's with that sudden shift?
なんかすごい、本当におめでとうって、すごく丁寧に言ってくれるからさ。
You say "Congratulations" so formally, it's nice.
おめでたいんだもの、だって。
Well, it is a celebratory occasion after all.
え、でも嬉しい、ありがとう！
But I'm so glad, thank you!
うん、次も。
Yeah, next up is...
うん、まだ早いか？
Yeah, is it still too early?
いいよ、大丈夫か。
It's fine, are you okay?
大丈夫。え、まだね、いっぱいあると思うからね、頑張ってね。
I'm fine. There's still a lot to come, so good luck!
頑張る！
I'll do my best!
うん、はるちゃん、じゃあ応援してね。
Yeah, cheer for me, Haru-chan.
応援する、見てるね。
I'll cheer for you. I'll be watching.
見てて、ありがとう！
Watch me, thank you!
バイバイ。
Bye-bye.
バイバイ、はるちゃん！またね、おめでとう、バイバイ、バイバイ！
Bye-bye, Haru-chan! See you, congratulations, bye-bye!
はるちゃんって、結構マイペースなんですよ。
Haru-chan goes at her own pace, you know.
どいつもこいつもなんだかやけに脳天気
Everyone here is somehow incredibly carefree
ちいとのアルゴリズム ねえきっとあるでしょう
There must be some kind of algorithm, right?
ちょっとやそっとのユーズドじゃもう胸騒ぎ
Just a little bit used is already making my heart race
頭の中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
My head is a total mess
ドンマイ兵がいくじがないの包囲定義
Never mind, the spineless soldiers define the siege
いけないいけない事柄なんてないから
Since there's no such thing as a forbidden act
イーアルサンスー ジャンケンポンでさあお遊戯
One, two, three, rock-paper-scissors, let's play
有耶無耶 ぽくで手負いに召されてく
Vaguely, I'm being summoned like a wounded beast
君はもうハイスピードだな
You are already at high speed
ハッチャメッチャなドラマ
Such a crazy drama
イーイーイーの殺生 愛ラブユーのだし
Yes, yes, yes, slaughter, using "I love you" as an excuse
四六時中 愛を頂戴
Give me love twenty-four seven
イーイーイー違和感 愛愛愛は奈落
Yes, yes, yes, discomfort, love, love, love is a bottomless pit
二分の一じゃ物足りない
Just a half of it is not enough
それじゃあ結局見えないあいつの胸の内
In the end, I still can't see what's in their heart
おあつらえ向きのうわべもいらないから
I don't need any tailor-made superficiality
先輩 後輩 えんちょちゃんき関係ない
Seniors, juniors, it doesn't matter
いざ尋常に勝負
Now, let's have a fair fight
君がもしもその気なら
If you are up for it,
ボイミーツガールが始まりそうならさ
if "boy meets girl" is about to begin
また見ぬワンシーン作り出す
Creating a scene yet unseen
クラップ 手放そう スイートだな
Clap, let it go, how sweet
ハッチャメッチャな修羅場
Such a crazy scene
意味深な妥協 曖昧な愛ある状況
Meaningful compromise, an ambiguous loving situation
四の五の言わず察して頂戴
Don't make excuses, just understand me
待って いちびるの年中 話半分だった
Wait, acting cocky all year, it was only half-hearted
自分の意思をどうにかしちゃい
Do something about my own free will
イーイーイーの殺生 愛ラブユーのだし
Yes, yes, yes, slaughter, using "I love you" as an excuse
四六時中 愛を頂戴
Give me love twenty-four seven
イーイーイー違和感 愛愛愛は奈落
Yes, yes, yes, discomfort, love, love, love is a bottomless pit
二分の一じゃもうたまらない
Just a half of it is unbearable
氷なんて溶かしちゃう 会いたいかもしれない
It'll melt the ice, I might want to see you
毎晩 既読1000回 足りないや
Read a thousand times every night, it's not enough
偶然を装って天使を装うな
Don't pretend it's a coincidence, don't play the angel
平和をちょっと乱してみせてよ
Try disturbing the peace a little
はい！というわけで、いいなずっきゅんでした！どうでしたか？
All right! And so, that was Iinazukkyun! How did you like it?
え、シルエットのさ、ここ、かっこよくなかった？ポンポン、ってせんの。
Hey, wasn't that silhouette part cool? Doing like "bam bam".
結構お気に入りポイントです。
It's one of my favorite points.
はい！どうだった？
Yes! How was it?
可愛いでしょ？改めて、新衣装。ね？
Cute, right? Once again, the new outfit. Right?
みこちと、ぽるちゃんともね、歌えて嬉しい！
I'm so happy I got to sing with Mikochi and Pol-chan!
まさかの、「ええっ！？」って思ってる人が出てもね、めっちゃ多かったと思うんだけど、お呼びしました、今回は。
I think many of you were surprised, wondering "What?!", but I invited them this time.
嬉しいです。
I'm really happy.
さあ、というわけで。
Now, with that said...
もう、結構歌ったね！うーん。
We've sung quite a lot already! Yeah.
なんか、そろそろウズウズしてる人たちが、いっぱいいる気がするの！
I feel like there are many people getting antsy around now!
ウズウズウズウズウズウズ！どこが一番ウズウズしてる？
Ants, ants, antsy! Who's getting the most antsy?
はい！というわけで、待ちができないので、ご紹介したいと思います。
All right! Since I can't wait, I'd like to introduce it.
誕生日といえば？
Speaking of birthdays...
誕生日グッズ！！！
Birthday merchandise!!!
今回の誕生日グッズはこちら！
Here is the birthday merchandise for this time!
はい！久々にタペストリーを出します。
Yes! It's been a while since I released a tapestry.
まず1つ目。B2タペストリー！
First up, the B2 tapestry!
こちらイラストはね、とてもクールな僕なんですけれども、
For this illustration, I look very cool, but...
しゃがむ先生に描いていただきました！
it was drawn by Syagamu-sensei!
あ、これ、龍違いとか言わないでね。龍、お前も好きだしお前も好きだぞ、みんな愛してる、龍です。
Ah, please don't say it's the wrong dragon. "I like you, and I like you too, I love you all" – it's that dragon.
めっちゃかっこいいよね！
It's super cool, isn't it?
強そうな龍と、強そうな僕。かっこいいでしょ？
A powerful-looking dragon and a powerful-looking me. Cool, right?
そして、2つ目は？
And the second item is...
なんとお腹いっぱいに食べちゃお餃子皿！
surprisingly, the "Eat Till You're Full Gyoza Plate"!
なんと、こちら、ロボ子先生が描いてくれました！
Amazingly, this was drawn by Roboco-sensei!
見て、なんか凄い、もう、
Look, it's really like, already...
いっぱい食べる気満々の 沼にハマってるロボことロボさ めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょう
Roboko and Robosa, who are stuck in the marsh and fully ready to eat, are super cute, right?
このお皿を使っていっぱいね 餃子なり何なり食べてください
Please use this plate to eat lots of gyoza or whatever you like!
お腹いっぱいになると幸せになるのでね
Because when you fill your stomach, you become happy.
はい！そして次は？
Yes! And next is...
ご飯を食べたら喉渇く
Once you eat, you get thirsty!
ちあーず！グラスですね
It's the Cheers! Glass.
ビール入れたっていいし お茶入れたっていいし ジュース入れたっていい
It's fine to put beer in it, tea in it, or juice in it!
美味しいもの飲んでいきましょう！
Let's drink delicious things!
こちらもなんとロボこ先生が描いてくれました 高性能だな
For this too, Roboko-sensei drew it. How high-spec!
可愛いすぎる こんなウィンクされたらいっぱい飲んだったってね いいですから
It's way too cute! Getting winked at like this makes you want to drink a lot, which is fine!
ぜひ、ええ、ご飯と飲み物
Please, with your meals and drinks...
食卓にお使いくださいまし
...please use them at your dining table.
今度僕も配信でね 使ってみようと思うので
I'm thinking of using them in my stream next time,
ぜひチェックしてみてください
so please check them out.
そして、まだまだあります！こちら、ドン！
And we still have more! Here, boom!
はい！僕の大好きなぬいぐるみ！
Yes! My favorite plushie!
本日も可愛いものができました
Another cute one is ready today.
見て！お座りしてるの、今回の。お座りぬいぐるみ
Look! It's sitting down this time. A sitting plushie.
ちゃんとロボサーもね、ここにいますよ（はい）
Robosa is also right here as well.
はい。今回はね、お座りのぬいぐるみなので
Yes. Since it's a sitting plushie this time,
そのままお部屋に飾ってもいいし
you can just display it in your room like this,
お出かけでもね、一緒に写真撮りやすいのかなと思います
or take it out with you, as I think it'll be easy to take photos together.
はい。いっぱい色んなところに連れてってあげてください
Yes. Please take it with you to many different places.
大切にしてね。無くさないでね。置いていかないでね
Treasure it, okay? Don't lose it. Don't leave it behind!
たくさん買ったっていいんだからね
You can buy as many as you want, you know!
そして、ボイスも出ます！
And we also have voice packs!
今回は、シチュエーションボイス「ぼく vs りゅう」
This time, it's the situation voice "Me vs. Dragon".
まじで、りゅうの名前さ、定まらんのよね
Seriously, the dragon's name hasn't been finalized.
みどりだっていいし、りゅうだっていいし、ドラゴンくんだっていいし、ドラちゃんだっていい。何だっていい
Midori is fine, Ryu is fine, Dragon-kun is fine, or Dora-chan is fine. Anything is fine!
おお、いいよね、ね
Oh, that's great, right?
はい、君に襲いかかるりゅうに、可愛さ勝負を挑む
Yes, challenging the dragon attacking you to a cuteness battle:
僕のお話、キュン
my story, heart-fluttering!
はい、どんなお話かはぜひ買って聞いてみてください
Yes, please purchase it and listen to find out what kind of story it is!
さぁ、最後に、こちら！
Now, finally, this one!
はい、今回のフルセット購入特典についてお話しします
Yes, I will talk about the full-set purchase bonuses this time.
えーまず1つ目
First, the first one:
えー数量限定版が、今回はあります"
There is a limited-quantity version this time!
数量限定版は、僕の直筆サインと
The limited-quantity version includes my handwritten autograph and...
箔押しの複製メッセージ入りのポストカードになります
...a postcard with a foil-stamped duplicate message.
はい。ぜひ、今回は僕のこの配信が終わったと
Yes. This time, right after my stream ends,
同時にカートがオープンしますので
the cart will open simultaneously,
そのタイミングで、ぜひ狙ってみてください
so please try to aim for that timing.
スタートダッシュの準備はいいか
Are you ready for a head start?
ぜひゲットしてくださいね
Please be sure to get it!
はい、もちろん通常版もあります。通常版は
Yes, of course, there is also a regular version. The regular version
僕の直筆サインはないんですけど、箔押し入りのね
doesn't have my handwritten autograph, but it has a foil-stamped...
サインとメッセージのポストカードがついてきますので、ぜひゲットしてください
...autograph and message postcard, so please get it!
そして、まだフルセット購入特典には
And furthermore, the full-set purchase bonuses also include
ボイスがつきます
bonus voices.
1つ目「きみとりゅうとよるのそら」
The first one is "You, the Dragon, and the Night Sky".
こちらは販売ボイスのね、少しあ後の時間帯のお話で
This is a story set a little bit after the main voice pack's events,
なんと時間軸が続いております
and believe it or not, the timeline is connected!
販売ボイスは、別に単体でも楽しめますけど
You can enjoy the main voice pack on its own,
特典ボイスも合わせると
but if you also listen to the bonus voice,
「え、あのあ後の続きがあるの？」って楽しめので、ぜひ聞いてほしいです
you can enjoy it thinking, "Oh, there's a continuation after that?" So please listen!
面白いよ
It's really fun!
そして、なんと、今回は、じゃん！
And surprisingly, this time, ta-da!
タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として
As a full-set purchase bonus for the talent premium goods,
2024年から、9月から発売がされた
which started selling in September 2024,
「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」で使用できるカードが、1枚ついてきます
you will get one card that can be used in the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME"!
同梱するカードは
The included card is
ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された
only for customers who purchase it on the
お客様のみの対象となります
Hololive Production Official Shop.
今回特典につくのは
The card included as a bonus this time
ゲームで、1枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールすることができるカード
is an Oshi Holomem Card where you can use just one in a game to show off your favorite member,
「推しホロメンカード」です！
the "Oshi Holomem Card"!
みんな欲しいっしょ、これ
You all want this, right?
1枚、今しか買えない
This single card is only available now!
ロボサーは買うべき
Robosa definitely should buy it.
強いよ！
It's really strong!
はい、というわけで
Okay, so anyway,
カードの詳細や遊び方については
regarding the card's details and how to play,
多分、僕から聞くより
rather than hearing it from me,
「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」の公式ホームページで確認した方が
checking the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME" official website
分かりやすいと思うので、ぜひチェックしてみてください
would be easier to understand, so please check it out.
はい、同梱するカードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください
Yes, please note that the included card is Japanese-version only.
No English, sorry.
グッズのカートオープンは、このあと配信終了後になりますので
The merchandise cart will open right after this stream ends,
みんな！
so everyone,
待機して買ってね！
please wait on standby and buy it!
いっぱい買ったっていい！
It's totally fine to buy lots of them!
そして！
And...
この後はなんと！
...what's coming up next is...
実は初めての
...actually, for the first time...
メインエ、アル、ア、イ、
...a Main E- Al- A- I...
アンコールライブがあります！
There will be an encore live!
お酒は飲んでも 飲まれるな！
You can drink alcohol, but don't let it drink you!
私、今日お酒飲んでない！
I haven't had any alcohol today!
ふふふふ！
Hehehe!
えー、アンコールとアルコール似てるんだわ！
Encore and alcohol sound so similar!
はい、というわけで、なんと今回はね、アンコールライブがありますので！
Yes, so this time, we have an encore live!
アンコールライブはね、みんながずっと僕に歌ってほしそうだった、あの曲を歌っちゃおうかなと思ってますので、
For the encore live, I think I'll sing that song everyone has wanted me to sing for a long time.
楽しみにしててくださーい！
So look forward to it!
なんか、せっかくだからね、写真撮影会とかね、ロボサーと密な空間で、
And since we are here, in a cozy space with the Robosa, with a photo session...
いっぱい見せちゃおうかなって、思っています！
I'm thinking of showing you a lot!
あ、メンバーのプレゼントもありがとね！みんなぜひ見ててください！
Oh, and thanks for the membership gifts! Make sure to check them out!
はい、というわけで...
Yes, and with that...
ロボサー、
Robosa,
早いけど、次が最後の曲になっちゃうみたいです。
it's quick, but it seems the next one will be the last song.
僕はもう、9才。
I am already nine years old.
9才になってるよ、ロボサー。ここまで成長を見届けてくれて、ありがとうね。
I'm nine years old, Robosa. Thank you for watching me grow up to this point.
これからもまだまだ僕は成長していくので、一緒に末永く楽しんでいきましょう！
I will keep growing from here on, so let's keep enjoying together for a long time to come!
最後の曲は、はじめにチラッと言っててんけど...
The last song, I mentioned it briefly at the beginning, but...
ドラゴンくんに乗りたいな！
I want to ride on the dragon!
一緒に頑張ってくれる？
Will you do your best with me?
ね、ドラゴンくん！
Right, Dragon-kun?
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is charmed
その眩しい笑顔に
by that dazzling smile of yours
果てない暗闇から飛び出そう
Let's break out of this endless darkness
Hold my hand
君と出逢ったとき
When I first met you,
子どもの頃 大切に
I remembered a place
想っていた場所を思い出したんだ
that I cherished as a child.
僕と踊ってくれないか
Won't you dance with me?
光と影の Winding road
On this winding road of light and shadow,
今でも 奴に夢中なの？
are you still crazy about him?
少しだけ 振り向きたくなるような
There are times when I feel like turning back...
時もあるけど
...even just a little, but...
愛と勇気と 誇りを持って
with love, courage, and pride,
闘うよ
I will fight!
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is charmed
この星の希望のかけら
by these fragments of hope on this planet.
きっと誰もが
Surely, anyone
永遠を手に入れたい
wants to possess eternity.
全然 気にしないフリしても
Even if I pretend not to care at all,
ほら君に恋してる
look, I'm in love with you.
果てない暗闇から飛び出そう
Let's break out of this endless darkness
Hold your hand
怒った顔も 疲れてる君も好きだけど
I love you when you're angry or tired...
あんなに飛ばして生きて 大確夫かなと思う
...but I wonder if you're okay, racing through life like that.
僕は...何気ない仕草に
I am spun around...
振り回されてる Sea side blue
...by your casual gestures, sea side blue.
それでも 奴に夢中なの？
But are you still crazy about him?
もっと聞きたいことがあったのに
There was more I wanted to ask, but...
二人の会話が 車の音に
...our conversation was drowned out by the cars...
阻まれて通りに舞うよ
...and it flutters away onto the street.
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is charmed
自分でも不思議なんだけど
It's strange even to me, but...
何かあると すぐに
whenever something happens...
君に電話したくなる
...I want to call you right away.
全然 気のないフリしても
Even if I pretend not to be interested at all...
結局君のことだけ見ていた
In the end, all I ever did was look at you
海の彼方へ
Let's jump out...
飛び出そうよ
...to the far ends of the sea!
Hold my hand
みんなー！
Everyone!
ろぼさー！
My Robosa!
今日は見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for watching today!
このあとはなんと！
After this, believe it or not...
メンバー限定でも歌います！
...I'll be singing for members-only too!
遊びにきてね！
Please come and join me!
グッズもめっちゃかわちいから
The merch is super cute too,
ゲットしてくれよな！
so make sure to get some!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
なんか君も遅いね、ドラゴンくん
You're kind of slow too, Mr. Dragon.